<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<template>
	<name>Collection Template</name>
	<briefDesc>For recording metadata about Datasets, Catalogues, Indexes, COllections, Registries, and Repositories</briefDesc>
	<tab name="general" label="General" order="1" />
	<tab name="description" label="Description" order="3" />
	<tab name="coverage" label="Coverage" order="2">
		<tooltip>Dates and Locations relating to collection</tooltip>
	</tab>
	<tab name="people" label="People" order="4">
		<tooltip>Information about contact(s)</tooltip>
	</tab>
	<tab name="subject" label="Subject" order="5" />
	<tab name="rights" label="Rights" order="6" />
	<tab name="management" label="Management" order="8" />
	<item name="type" label="Type" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" defaultValue="Collection" readonly="readonly" editPerm="admin" tab="general" />
	<item name="name" label="Title" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" maxLength="80" class="required" tab="general">
		<tooltip>This is the title of the data collection. It needs to be unique, i.e. do not use a title that is identical to an existing publication that is related to and/or underpinned by the data.&#xA;&#xA;Titles that are descriptive of the actual data are best. Try to include key distinctive characteristics that would provide information for potential users to determine if the data might be useful to them. These may include information specific to the entities studied, survey data, observations, images collected, location, time, and temporal or spatial coverage.&#xA;&#xA;Examples:&#xA;Net levels of greenhouse gas emission and sources in the New South Wales Hunter Valley, 1990 - 1998.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="abbrName" label="Brief Title" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" maxLength="255" tab="general">
		<tooltip>Please include a brief title if your title is very long</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="altName" label="Alternate Title" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" maxLength="255" tab="general">
		<tooltip>If there is an alternative title for your data collection, please include it here.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="subType" label="Collection Type" fieldType="RadioButton" saveType="single" class="required" tab="general">
		<tooltip>Catalogue or Index - a collection of descriptions describing the content of one or more collective works at the item level.&#xA;Collection - compiled content created as separate and independent works and assembled into a collective whole&#xA;Registry - a collection of registry objects compiled to support the business of a given community&#xA;Repository - a collection of physical or digital objects compiled for information and documentation purposes and/or for storage and safekeeping&#xA;Dataset - a collection of physical or digital objects generated by research activities.</tooltip>
		<option value="dataset" label="Dataset" />
		<option value="catalogueOrIndex" label="Catalogue or Index" />
		<option value="collection" label="Collection" />
		<option value="registry" label="Registry" />
		<option value="repository" label="Repository" />
	</item>
	<item name="ownerGroup" label="Group Affiliation" fieldType="Combobox" saveType="single" class="required" tab="general">
		<tooltip>Please choose the group the collection is affiliated with</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="doi" label="DOI - Digitan Object Identifier" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="general">
		<tooltip>The Digital Object Identifier for this record.<br/>Please note that if this does not already exist a DOI will be created when the record is published</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="metaLang" label="Metadata Language" fieldType="Combobox" saveType="single" tab="general">
		<tooltip>Please select the language that you are using to describe this data</tooltip>
		<option value="en" label="English" />
		<option value="zh" label="Chinese" />
	</item>
	<item name="dataLang" label="Data Language" fieldType="Combobox" saveType="single" tab="general">
		<tooltip>Please select the language the data is in</tooltip>
		<option value="en" label="English" />
		<option value="zh" label="Chinese" />
	</item>
	<item name="significanceStatement" label="Significance Statement" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" maxLength="4000" tab="description">
		<tooltip>What is significant about this dataset. For example:&#xA;&#xA;The first Australian full talking film.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="briefDesc" label="Brief Description" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" maxLength="4000" class="needed"  tab="description">
		<tooltip>A brief summary about the data</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="fullDesc" label="Full Description" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" maxLength="4000"  tab="description">
		<tooltip>The description should be as rich as possible. If applicable, include: the scope; details of what is being studied or recorded; methodologies used, information about any instruments that were used to produce and/or collect the data; relevant standards used; conditions under which the study or research occured or the data was collected, etc&#xA;If there were any problems or other issues with methods used to produce and/or collect the data, please include those as well.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="email" label="Contact Email" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" class="needed email" tab="people" />
	<item name="postalAddress" label="Contact Address" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" tab="people" />
	<item name="phone" label="Contact Phone Number" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="people" />
	<item name="fax" label="Contact Fax Number" fieldType="TextFieldMulti"  saveType="multiple" tab="people" />
	<item name="websiteAddress" label="Website Address" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="people" />
	<item name="creator" label="Creators" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="people">
		<tooltip>Please record the names of the persons who created the data.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="supervisor" label="Supervisors" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="people">
		<tooltip>Please record the name of the person identified as supervisor in relation to the creation of the data. (Note that this may be  the same as the Primary Contact.)</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="collaborator" label="Collaborators" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="people">
		<tooltip>Please record the names of any other collaborators in the research project which created the data.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="anzforSubject" label="Fields of Research" fieldType="ComboBoxMulti" saveType="multiple" class="needed" tab="subject">
		<tooltip>Include Fields of Research terms and corresponding classification codes to be associated with the resource being described. The Fields of Research Classfication can be found at the following URL.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.arc.gov.au/applicants/codes.htm#FOR</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="anzseoSubject" label="Socio-Economic Objective" fieldType="ComboBoxMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="subject">
		<tooltip>Include terms and corresponding classification codes to be associated with the resource being described. Information on the Socio-Economic Objectives Classication Codes can be found at the following URL.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.arc.gov.au/applicants/codes.htm#SEO</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="locSubject" label="Keywords" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="subject">
		<tooltip>Record keywords describing the activity. 5-10 keywords will normally be sufficient. The keywords must be specific enough for researchers with similar interests to find your activity.&#xA;&#xA;If you need assistance in selecting keywords, there are many thesauri that may be helpful. Please use one appropriate to your discipline. If you are unable to identify a discipline specific classification scheme, you may wish to use the Library of Congress Classification scheme available at http://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/lcco/</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="anztoaSubject" label="Type of Research Activity" fieldType="RadioButton" saveType="single" tab="subject">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, assign a research activity classficiation. There are four set values that can be assigned. Please choose one.</tooltip>
		<option value="ed" label="Experimental development" />
		<option value="ar" label="Applied Research" />
		<option value="sbr" label="Strategic basic research" />
		<option value="pbr" label="Pure basic research" />
	</item>
	<item name="coverageDates" label="Date Coverage" fieldType="Table" saveType="table" tab="coverage">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, please indicate a date range relevant to the content of the material described.&#xA;1990 - 2005&#xA;2011-05-29 - 2011-12-31&#xA;2012-06-21T11:49:53+10:00 - 2012-07-02T15:21+10:00</tooltip>
		<column name="dateFrom" label="Date From" fieldType="TextField" class="date" />
		<column name="dateTo" label="Date To" fieldType="TextField" class="date" />
	</item>
	<item name="coverageDateText" label="Time Period" fieldType="TextFieldMulti" saveType="multiple" tab="coverage">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, please describe the time period during which the data was collected, observations were made, images were created or the time period that the resource is linked to intellectually or thematically. Examples include:&#xA;18th Century&#xA;World War II</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="coverageArea" label="Geospatial Location" fieldType="Table" saveType="table" tab="coverage">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, please include geospatial location information relevant to the research dataset/collection. This information may describe a geographical area where the data was collected, a place which is the subject of the collection or a location which is the focus of an activity e.g. co-ordinates or place name.</tooltip>
		<column name="covAreaType" label="Location Type" fieldType="Combobox">
			<option value="text" label="Text" />
			<option value="gml" label="OpenGIS Geography Markup Language (GML) Encoding Standard" />
			<option value="gmlKmlPolyCoords" label="KML long/lat co-ordinates from GML defining a polygon" />
			<option value="gpx" label="the GPS Exchange Format" />
			<option value="iso31661" label="ISO 3166-1 Country Codes" />
			<option value="iso31662" label="ISO 3166-2 Country Subdivision Codes" />
			<option value="iso19139dcmiBox" label="DCMI Box notation conformant with iso 19139" />
			<option value="kml" label="Keyhole Markup Language developed for use with Google Earth" />
			<option value="kmlPolyCoords" label="Keyhol Markup Language co-ordinates defining a polygon" />
			<option value="dcmiPpoint" label="Spatial Location Information in DCMI Point Notation" />
		</column>
		<column name="covAreaValue" fieldType="TextField" />
	</item>
	<item name="citationYear" label="Year of data publication" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="description">
		<tooltip>The year the data was first published for citation purposes. If this field is not populated when publishing it will default to the year it is published in ANU Data Commons</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="citationCreator" label="Creator for Citation" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="description">
		<tooltip>The creator of the data for citation purposes. Defaults to 'The Australian National University'. For example:&#xA;&#xA;Smith, G., Jones, J.&#xA;Australian Phenomics Facility&#xA;Research School of Earth Sciences, The Australian National University</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="citationPublisher" label="Publisher for Citation" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="description">
		<tooltip>The publisher of the data.  Defaults to 'The Australian National University Data Commons'. For example:&#xA;&#xA;Australian Data Archive&#xA;Incorporated Research Institutions for Seismology</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="publication" label="Publications" fieldType="TableVertical" saveType="table" tab="description">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, please include information about any publications that relate to the collection/dataset&#xA;For example:&#xA;Identifier Type: International Standard Serial Number&#xA;Identifier Value: 0278-7393&#xA;Publication Reference: Heathcote, A. (2003) Item recognition memory and the ROC. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory and Cognition, 29, 1210-1230.</tooltip>
		<column name="pubType" label="Identifier Type" fieldType="Combobox">
			<option value="ark" label="ARK Persistent Identifier Scheme" />
			<option value="doi" label="Digital Object Identifier" />
			<option value="ean13" label="International Article Number" />
			<option value="eissn" label="Electronic International Standard Serial Number" />
			<option value="handle" label="HANDLE System Identifier" />
			<option value="infouri" label="'info' URI scheme" />
			<option value="local" label="identifier unique within a local context" />
			<option value="purl" label="Persistent Uniform Resource Locator" />
			<option value="uri" label="Uniform Resource Identifier" />
			<option value="issn" label="International Standard Serial Number" />
			<option value="isbn" label="International Standard Book Number" />
			<option value="istc" label="International Standard Text Code http://www.istc-international.org/html" />
			<option value="upc" label="Universal Product Code" />
			<option value="urn" label="Uniform Resource Name" />
		</column>
		<column name="pubValue" label="Identifier Value" fieldType="TextField" />
		<column name="pubTitle" label="Publication Reference" fieldType="TextArea" />
	</item>
	<item name="relatedWebsites" label="Related Websites" fieldType="Table" saveType="table" tab="description">
		<tooltip>If appropriate, please include a URL and Notes for any websites that relate to the resource being described. For example:&#xA;&#xA;URL: http://anusf.anu.edu.au/index.php&#xA;&#xA;Title: ANU Supercomputing Facility</tooltip>
		<column name="relatedWebURL" label="URL" fieldType="TextField" />
		<column name="relatedWebTitle" label="Title" fieldType="TextField" />
	</item>
	<item name="accessRights" label="Access Rights" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" tab="rights">
		<tooltip>Enter a statement about access (or access conditions) to the resource. This will include access restrictions or embargoes based on privacy, security or other policies.&#xA;&#xA;Examples:&#xA;Contact Chief Investigator to negotiate access to the data&#xA;&#xA;Embargoes until 1 year after publication of the research&#xA;&#xA;Open Access allowed (see rights held in and over resource below)</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="rightsStatement" label="Rights held in and over the data" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" tab="rights">
		<tooltip>Include information on copyright, licences and other intellectual property rights.&#xA;&#xA;Examples:&#xA;This dataset is made available under the Public Domain Dedication and Licence v1.0. Full text can be found at http://www.opendatacommons.org/licences/pddl/1.0/&#xA;&#xA;Creative Commons Licence (CC BY or CC BY-SA or CC BY-ND or CC BY-NC or CC BY-NC-SA or CC BY-NC-ND) is assigned to this data. Details of the licence can be found at http://creativecommons.org.au/licences.&#xA;&#xA;The (name) licence that controls this data is available at (URL)</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="licenceType" label="Licence Type" fieldType="Combobox" saveType="single" tab="rights">
		<tooltip>Further information on the licence types can be found at http://www.ausgoal.gov.au/the-ausgoal-licence-suite&#xA;&#xA;Attribution - This licence lets others distribute, remix, tweak, and build upon your work, even commercially, as long as they credit you for the original creation. This is the most accomodating of licences offered. Recommended for maximum dissemination and use of licenced materials.&#xA;Attribution-shareAlike - This licence lets others remix, tweak and build upon your work even for commercial purposes, as long as they credit you and licence their new creations under identical terms. This licence is often compared to 'copyleft' free and open source software licences. All new works based on yours will carry the same licence, so any derivatives will also allow commercial use. This is the licence used by Wikipedia, and is recommended for materials that would benefit from incorporating content from Wikipedia and similarly licenced projects.&#xA;Attribution-NoDerivatives - This licence allows for redistribution, commercial and non-commercial, as long as it is passed along unchanged and in whole, with credit to you.&#xA;Attribution-NonCommercial - This licence lets other remix, tweak and build upon your work non-commercially, and although their new works must also acknowledge you and be non-commercial, they don't have to licence their derivative works on the same terms.&#xA;Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike - This licence lets others remix, tweak, and build upon your work non-commercially, as long as they credit you and licence their new creations under the identical terms.&#xA;Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives - This licence is the most restrictive of AusGoal's six main licences, only allowing others to download your works and share them with others as long as they credit you, but they can't change them in any way or use them commercially.&#xA;General Public Licence - The GNU General Public Licence is a free, copyleft licence for software and other kinds of works. Further information can be found at http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html&#xA;AusGoal Restrictive Licence - This licence has been developed specifically for mateiral that may contain personal or other confidential information. It may also be used for other reasons, including material to be licenced under some form of limiting or restrictive condiation (e.g. a time limit on use, or payment arrangements others than an initial once-only fee).</tooltip>
		<option value="CC-BY" label="Attribution" />
		<option value="CC-BY-SA" label="Attribution-SharedAlice" />
		<option value="CC-BY-ND" label="Attribution-NoDervis" />
		<option value="CC-BY-NC" label="Attribution-NonCommercial" />
		<option value="CC-BY-NC-SA" label="Attribution-NonCommercial-SharedAlike" />
		<option value="CC-BY-NC-ND" label="Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDervis" />
		<option value="GPL" label="GNU General Public Licence" />
		<option value="AusGoalRestrictive" label="AusGoal Restrictive Licence" />
		<option value="NoLicence" label="No licence" />
		<option value="Unknown/Other" label="Unknown licence or record provider defined licence" />
	</item>
	<item name="licence" label="Licence" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" tab="rights">
		<tooltip>Licence Information</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="dataLocation" label="Data Location" fieldType="TextArea" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>Include where the data is located&#xA;&#xA;Example:&#xA;This data is located at (URL or physical location)</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="dataRetention" label="Retention Period" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>Include the period of time that the data must be retained. This must be in line with institutional/funding body or legistlative retention&#xA;&#xA;Examples:&#xA;7 years&#xA;&#xA;Until 31st December 2016&#xA;&#xA;Indefinately</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="disposalDate" label="Disposal Date" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>The identified disposal date for this data is (date)</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="dataExtent" label="Extent or Quantity" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>Enter the number of files that comprise the research dataset/collection</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="dataSize" label="Data Size" fieldType="TextField" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>Record the file size of the data in KB, MB, GB, TB, etc. If you are unsure, please consult your IT support person.</tooltip>
	</item>
	<item name="dataMgmtPlan" label="Data Management Plan" fieldType="RadioButton" saveType="single" tab="management">
		<tooltip>Indicate if there is a data management plan for this data. Information on data management plans is found at http://libguides.anu.edu.au/datamanagement/</tooltip>
		<option value="yes" label="Yes" />
		<option value="no" label="No" />
	</item>
</template>
